# OMAR HABASH Senior UI Developer

# **SUMMARY**

To contribute experience, code, design, and leadership within a talented team dedicated to creating an impactful product at a rapidly growing company. I'm no stranger to fast-paced environments where time is money and quality is paramount.

# CONTACT

ContactOmarNow@gmail.com 214-470-5176

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Tarrant County College**

Associates Computer Science - 3.8 GPA

#### **Rose State**

FAA Private Pilots' License

## LINKS

https://www.zayntek.com https://fornida.com https://www.fornida.net https://habitatcommons.com https://dash.fornida.com https://deadsoxy.com

# HEADLES COMMERCE AWARD RECIPIENT

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Fornida**

Plano, Texas 06/2018 - Current

#### **Senior Software Developer**

Trained and managed a team of developers, played a central role in launching the company's ecommerce & ERP software stack. My tenure was marked by achievements that transformed Fornida's autonomous software landscape, Angular, NodeJS, Stripe, Mongo, Amazon SP-API, Microsoft Graph, BigCommerce

#### ZaynTek.com & Fornida.com

Leveraged Angular to build dynamic E-commerce storefronts - featuring a one-of-a-kind frontend editing experience that redefined product management for site administrators. Our NestJS backend facilitated integrations, including BigCommerce, for enhanced e-commerce capabilities. With tens of thousands of carefully categorized products we had to build robust SEO features which provided google with the latest product descriptions, reviews, prices, images and even stock levels. Today we proudly occupy first page results in google for most of our industries top products

#### **Internal Listing Dashboard**

This dashboard allowed admins to add 1000s of products to our e-com stores with ease. By providing a list of part numbers this tool would reach out to various APIs to combine product images, descriptions, tech specs, downloads, stock levels and sales history to create product pages which then automatically updated each sites' sitemap and informed google of new data.

#### **Microsoft Business Central ERP Dashboard**

Today, Fornida's employees all use "DASH," a custom ERP dashboard that combines all our major business processes in one software. It gives salespeople instant access to their performance metrics, quotes, orders, and invoices. Admins can tailor access per role, enhancing each user's experience. DASH integrates with platforms like BigCommerce, Amazon, Shopify, and eBay, centralizing orders into standardized sales orders. For warehouse staff, it provides live KPIs like open orders and pending shipments, and for drop-shipped orders, it automatically updates the BuyReport, advising on procurement and streamlining purchase order creation.

#### JOMA Tech

Dallas, Texas 02/2018 - 10/2020

#### **Senior Software Developer**

Built an award winning CMS and e-commerce theming platform. It used BigCommerce API's and Google's Angular to provide JOMA Tech's clients with advanced control over content and design of their storefronts. This unique combination of tools allowed for ultra modern features which reinvented how store owners interact with their customers on the web.

#### **SUCCESS Partners®**

#### **Frontend Developer**

Dallas, Texas 03/2015 - 02/2018

SKILLS

Frontend Developer specializing in creating user-facing elements for ecommerce sites, with a strong foundation in development and design. Successfully designed, developed, and maintained over 30 ecommerce sites on Magento and BigCommerce. Led the migration of 14 Magento sites to BigCommerce, and developed a unique BigCommerce app that converts user 'points' into discounts, automatically syncing with accounting records. Used javascript and PHP

